Mss.B.P212
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to Sir James Paget, April 5, 1882; 7x4-1/2; Suileim-bey (?)
    Hyderabad, L.S. 4p.with 2p.enclosures in Arabic(?), and add. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Asks that he give all possible courtesies to his two sons.
  - Letter to [Sir James] Paget, April 22, 1882; 7x4-1/2; Tyndall, John, 1820-1893
    Saturday A.L.S. 1p.,end. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Has just been informed that Darwin will be buried in Westminster Abby.
  - Letter to [Sir James] Paget, April 24, [1882]; 7x4-1/2; Tyndall, John, 1820-1893
    Monday A.L.S. 1p.,end. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Notifies him that Darwin is to be laid on Wednesday next in Westminster Abby.
  - Letter to [George J. Romanes], Jan. 11, 1883; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Ribot, Th. (Théodule), 1839-1916
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. In French. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Concerning medical publications.
  - Letter to ----, April 1, 1883; 5-1/2x3-1/2; Thompson, Henry, Sir, 1820-1904
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Is glad to give her his signature.
  - Letter to [George John] Romanes, July 15, 1883; 7x4-1/2; De la Rue, Warren, 1815-1889
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection... ) Will join committee for portrait of Burdon-Sanderson.
  - Letter to G[eorge] J[ohn] Romanes, Aug. 6, 1883; 5-1/4x3-1/2; Simon, John, 1818-1897
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Subscribes to portrait of Burdon-Sanderson.
  - Letter to the Undersecretary of State for War, Oct. 27, 1883; 12-3/4x8; Nordenfelt, Thorsten, 1842-1920
    London, A.L.S. 4p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Concerning a new gun-powder.
  - Letter to [George John] Romanes, Dec. 16, 1883; 6x4; Gray, Asa, 1810-1888
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 3p. (see Sir James Paget Collection...) Comments on evolution.
  - Note to [Sir James Paget], Jan., 1884; 3-1/2x4-1/2; Clark, Andrew, 1826-1893
    A.N.in 3rd.P. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Thanks you note, probably enclosed with a gift.
  - Letter to [Sir James] Paget, Jan. 10, 1884; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Is delighted his fossil specimens are all truned over to the museum. Is also delighted that his coming retirement is so well handled.
  - Letter to Sir James Paget, Jan. 19, 1884; 7x4-1/2; Carpenter, William Benjamin, 1813-1885
    London, A.L.S. 4p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Forwards a publication. Concerning their friendship.
  - Letter to [George John] Romanes, March 11, 1884; 7x4-1/2; Mivart, St. George Jackson, 1827-1900
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Concerning publications.
  - Letter to [Sir James] Paget, June 15, 1884; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 3p.and end. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Recommends a woman who wishes to become a nurse.
  - Letter to [George John Romanes], Oct. 13, 1884; 6-1/2x4-1/4; Espinas, Alfred Victor, 1844-1922
    Bordeaux, A.L.S. 2p. In French, (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Concerning his work: Mental evolution in animals.
  - Letter to Sir James Paget, June 29, 1885; 7x4-1/2; Chadwick, Edwin, 1800-1890
    Mortlake, A.L.S. 4p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Concerning improvements needed to help purify the air.
  - Letter to Sir James [Paget], July 2, 1885; 7x4-1/2; Brown-Séquard, Charles Edouard, 1817-1894
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. (see Sir James Paget. Correspondence... ) Thanks for his letter of congratulations.
  - Letter to "My dear Niece", Dec. 23, 1885; 7x4-1/2; Paget, George Edward, 1809-1892
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 4p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Thanks for her letter congratulating him on his knighthood.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Ethel Duncan] Romanes, Jan. 11, 1886; 7x4-1/2; Spencer, Herbert, 1820-1903
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Sir James Paget. Collections...) Cannot accept invitation. Glad G.J. Romanes called and is sorry he missed him.
  - Letter to Sir James [Paget], Feb. 11, 1886; 6-1/4x4; Turner, William, Sir, 1832-1916
    Edinburgh, A.L.S. 4p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Is accepting a knighthood and wishes to thank him for his favors.
  - Letter to [George John] Romanes, March 16, 1886; 7x4-1/2; Flower, William Henry, 1831-1899
    London, A.L.S. 1p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Thanks for favor.
  - Letter to [George John] Romanes, April 15, 1886; 7-1/2x5-1/2; Weismann, August, 1834-1914
    London, A.L.S. 2p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Would like to meet him and suggests a date.
  - Letter to Sir James [Paget], May 4, 1886; 7x4-1/2; Burdon-Sanderson, J. (John), Sir, 1828-1905
    Bournemouth, Sunday. [before] A.L.S. 2p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Has to lecture, therefore cannot meet Pasteur.
  - Letter to Sir James Paget, May 4, 1886; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Horsley, Victor, Sir, 1857-1916
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. (see Sir James Paget. collection...) Concerning Pasteur and rabies.
  - Letter to Sir James [Paget], May 24, 1886; 6x4; Lister, Joseph, Baron, 1827-1912
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Sir James Paget Collection...) Hopes to attend the meeting.
  - Letter to Sir James Paget, bart., Jan. 26, 1887; 8x5; Abel, Frederick Augustus, Sir, 1826-1902
    London, A.L.S. 1p. (see Sir James Paget Collection...) Sends him pamphlets.
  - Letter to [Sir James] Paget, April 9, 1887; 7x4-1/2; Tyndall, John, 1820-1893
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Describes his symptoms and says he is much better.
  - Letter to [Sir James] Paget, July 3, 1887; 7x4-1/2; Tyndall, John, 1820-1893
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Concerning honors heaped on them.
  - Letter to Sir James Paget, July 18, 1887; 7x4-1/2; Kölliker, Albert, 1817-1905
    Würzburg, A.L.S. 3p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Asks for help in locating his son a good job as a chemist.
  - Letter to Miss Paget, Oct. 25, 1887; 7x4-1/2; Thomson, J. J. (Joseph John), 1856-1940
    A.L.S. 2p.,end. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Explains a problem in physics.
  - Letter to [Charles Edouard] Brown-Séquard, Nov. 17, 1887; 6-1/2x4-1/4; Lesseps, Ferdinand de, 1805-1894
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. In French. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Recommends a man for election.
  - Letter to Sir James [Paget], Jan. 16, 1888; 7x4-1/2; Duncan, J. Matthews (James Matthews), 1826-1890
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Thanks for his "Morton" lectures and praises them.
  - Letter to Sir James [Paget], Jan. 30, 1888; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Gueneau du Mussy, N.
    A.L.S. 2p. In French. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Compliments him on his work on cancer.
  - Letter to [Sir James] Paget, Jan. 30, 1888; 7x4-1/2; Hannover, Adolph, 1814-1894
    Copenhagen, A.L.S. 4p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Concerning cancer. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Sir James [Paget], Feb. 5, 1888; 7x4-1/2 and 9x7; Brown-Séquard, Charles Edouard, 1817-1894
    A.L.S. 3p. Enc.of sketch by Chevreul. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Concerning medicine. Forwards sketch of Chevreul. Will send autographs of Agassiz etc. if he can locate them.
  - Letter to [Sir James Paget], Feb. 10, 1888; 5x5; Verneuil, A. A. (Aristide Auguste Stanislas), 1823-1895
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. In French. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Invites him to a meeting.
  - Letter to Sir James [Paget], Feb. 28, 1888; 7x4-1/2; Billings, John S. (John Shaw), 1838-1913
    Washington, A.L.S. 3p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Delighted he accepts the invitation. Cancer. Johns Hopkins hospital.
  - Letter to Sir James [Paget], March 1, 1888; 7x4-1/2; Brown-Séquard, Charles Edouard, 1817-1894
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Sends photograph to his daughter. Hopes to acquire Chevreul's autograph shortly.
  - Letter to [Charles Edouard Brown-Séquard], March 2, 1888; 7x4-1/2; Bouchard, Charles Jacques, 1837-1915
    A.L.S. 3p. In French. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Is leaving Algeria. Concerning Pasteur's experiments on cholera as being done in the Académie.
  - Letter to Sir James Paget, March 7, 1888; 8x5; Carpenter, Wm. Lant (William Lant), 1841-1890
    Halifax, A.L.S. 4p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Concerning telegraphy.
  - Letter to Sir James Paget, bart., March 12, 1888; 7x4-1/4; Ferrier, David, 1843-1928
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Asks that his memoir on Sir George Burrows be printed.
  - Letter to Miss Paget, March 21, 1888; 3-1/2x4-1/2; Brown-Séquard, Charles Edouard, 1817-1894
    A.L.S. 1p. Enc. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Encloses letters from Verneuil and Bouchard for her autograph collection.
  - Letter to Jo[h]n Trotman, June 5, 1888; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Snider,
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Concerning his patents and inventions.
  - Letter to Mrs. Joseph W. Swan, England, June 18, 1888; 11x8-1/2; Edison, Thomas A., (Thomas Alva), 1847-1931
    Orange, Typed L.S. 1p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Concerning the phonograph.
  - Letter to Sir James Paget, January 11, 1889; 6x4; Bramwell, F. J. (Frederick Joseph), 1818-1903 (Box 2)
    Manchester, A.L.S. 2p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Thanks for letter of congratulations.
  - Letter to [Sir James Paget], June 5, 1889; 8-3/4x7; Roux, Monsieur (Emile), 1853-1933
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. In French. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Thanks for his courtesy while in London.
  - List of members of the Philosophical Club, Nov. 21, 1889; Royal Society of London
  - Letter to Prof. [William] Thomson, [baron Kelvin], Dec. 2, 1890; 7x4-1/2; Hertz, Heinrich, 1857-1894
    London, A.L.S. 1p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Will try to see him in his laboratory.
  - Letter to [Sir James] Paget, Jan. 20, 1891; 7x4-1/2; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Concerning a resolution on Owen. His ideas on Owen's work.
    Unlocated, March 2011.
  - List of members of the Philosophical Club, Apr. 28, 1892; Royal Society of London
  - Letter to Lady [Lydia North] Paget, May 1, 1892; 6x3-3/4; Horsley, Victor, Sir, 1857-1916
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Thanks for present.
  - Letter to Sir James [Paget], May 31, 1892; 7x4-1/2; Virchow, Rudolf Ludwig Karl, 1821-1902
    Berlin, A.L.S. 3p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Cannot accept invitation.
  - Letter to [Sir James Paget], Nov. 25, 1892; 8-3/4x5-1/2; Virchow, Rudolf Ludwig Karl, 1821-1902
    Berlin, A.L.S. 2p. In German. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...)
  - Letter to Sir James [Paget], Nov. 24, 1894; 7x4-1/2; Kelvin, William Thomson, Baron, 1824-1907
    Glasgow, A.L.S. 2p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Asks him to propose toasts at the dinner of the Royal Society.
  - Letter to Dr. Dawson Turner, March 15, 1895; Lodge, Oliver, Sir, 1851-1940
  - Letter to Sir James Paget, Nov. 14, 1895; 8x5; Ramsay, William, 1852-1916
    London, A.L.S. 4p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Concerning a meeting at the University of London.
  - Letter to Sir James Paget, April 18, 1896; 6-1/4x4; Crookes, William, 1832-1919
    London, Typed L.S. 2p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Asks that he become a supernumerary of the Philosophical club, rather than resigning from it.
  - Letter to Miss Paget, June 22, 1898; 7x4-1/2; Galton, Francis, Sir, 1822-1911
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Will examine the memory of a 5 year old.
  - Letter to Miss Paget, June 29, 1898; 7x4-1/2; Galton, Francis, Sir, 1822-1911
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Will examine the boy with the remarkable memory. Invites her to dinner.
  - Letter to Miss Paget, Aug. 5, 1898; 7x4-1/2; Galton, Francis, Sir, 1822-1911
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Concerning a remarkable example of memory in a 5year old boy.
  - Letter to [Sylvanus Phillips?] Thompson, March 23, 1899; 7-1/2x5; Christie, William Henry Mahony, Sir, 1845-1922
    London, A.L.S. 2p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Concerning the attempts to take photographs of Saturn.
  - Letter to Miss [Mary Maud] Paget, May 8, 1899; 8x5; Thiselton-Dyer, William T. (William Turner), 1843-1928
    Kew, A.L.S. 2p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Botany.
  - Letter to Mary [Maud Paget], May 23, 1903; 7x4-1/2; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Sunningdale, A.L.S. 4p (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Concerning figures in Crome's works.
  - Letter to Miss Paget, Nov. 9, 1904; 7x4-1/2; Swan, Joseph Wilson, 1828-1914
    London, A.L.S. 2p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Thanks for her letter of congratulations.
  - Letter to the British Association for the Advancement of Science, Feb. 20, 1905; 7x4-1/2; Maxim, Hiram S. (Hiram Stevens), 1840-1916
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Wishes to know if he is arrears in fees.
  - Letter to Mr.Paget, Feb. 21, 1908; 5-1/2x4-1/4; Hawkes, Aubrey
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Will join his society, if need be.
  - Letter to [Stephen?] Paget, Feb. 22, 1908; 7x4-1/2; Huggins, William, Sir, 1824-1910
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Gives his name as a vice-president of the society.
  - Letter to Mr. Paget, February 22, 1908; Huggins, William, Sir, 1824-1910
    Regarding vice presidency of [Research] Defence Society.
  - Letter to Stephen Paget, Feb. 28, 1908; 7x4-1/2; Geikie, Archibald, Sir, 1835-1924
    London, A.L.S. 2p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Will let his name appear as a member, but not as Vice-President, since it might appear that he was committing the Royal Society if it did.
  - Letter to [Stephen?] Paget, June 14, 1908; 7x4-1/2; Treves, Frederick, Sir, 1853-1923
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Cannot attend meeting.
  - Letter to Stephen Paget, London, June 18, [1915]; 3-1/2x4-1/2; Rayleigh, John William Strutt, Baron, 1842-1919
    A.L.in 3rd.P.on postal card. 1p.and add. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Cannot attend.
  - Letter to [Stephen] Paget, March 28, 1918; 6x4-1/2; Myers, Charles Samuel, 1873-
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 1p. (see Sir James paget. Collection...) Has been ill and cannot attend meetings.
  - Letter to Stephen Paget, London, June 24, 1919; 3-1/2x4-1/2; Osler, William, Sir, 1849-1919
    A.L.S.on postal card. 1p.and add. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Cannot attend meeting.
  - Letter to "My dear Master", Oct. 5, 1921; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Rutherford, Ernest, 1871-1937
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 2p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Asks for some publications to scan before the meeting.
  - Letter to ----, Dec. 1, 1921; 7x4-1/2; Dewar, James, Sir, 1842-1923
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection... ) Physics.
  - Letter to [Stephen Paget], Feb. 22, 1924; 7x4-1/2; Geikie, Archibald, Sir, 1835-1924
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Is in sympathy with the organization but, as an officer of the Royal Society, cannot participate prominently in it.
  - Autographs., Paget, James, Sir, 1814-1899
    D.S. 11 items. Various sizes. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...)
  - Letter to ----., 7x4-1/2; Babbage, Charles, 1791-1871
    A.L. 1p. Postscript. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Concerning chloroform and operations.
  - Letter to [C.E. Brown-Séquard]., 8x5-1/4; Best, Paul
    L. 1p. In French. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Thanks for invitation to dinner.
  - Letter to Sir James Paget, 7x4-1/2; Burdon-Sanderson, J. (John), Sir, 1828-1905
    Paris, Sunday. A.L.S. 4p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Concerning Pasteur and rabies. Concerning Pasteur and other experiments.
  - Letter to ----., 8x5-1/4; Charcot, J. M. (Jean Martin), 1825-1893
    A.L.S. 3p. In French. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Introduces and recommends Dr. Anderson.
  - Letter to "Dear Mr. Robert", 7-1/4x4-1/2; Clark, James, Sir, 1788-1870
    Thursday morning. A.L.S. 3p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Asks for an appointment for James Paget.
  - Letter to Sir James [Paget], 7x4-1/2; Clark, Andrew, 1826-1893
    Wednesday. A.L.S. 1p.,end. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Accepts invitation.
  - Letter to "My dear Sir Robert.", 7-1/4x4-1/2; Clark, James, Sir, 1788-1870
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Withdraws his recommendation of John Birkett and recommends Paget.
  - Letter to Mrs. Thompson, 7x4-1/2; Clark, Mat
    Saturday. A.L.S. 1p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Sends autographed book.
  - Letter to ----, 8x6; Cuvier, Georges, baron, 1769-1832
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Is ill and cannot attend.
  - Letter to the Master and Fellows of Caius College, Monday evening, undated; Photocopy.; Darwin, Charles, 1809-1882
  - Autograph fragment of a letter, undated; 2 pages, photocopies.; Darwin, Charles, 1809-1882
  - Letter to [George John] Romanes, 7x4-1/2; Ellerton, John Lodge, 1801-1873
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Hopes they returned well. Asks if they could use the enclosed [which is wanting].
  - Letter to [Sir George] Grove, 7x4-1/2; Falconer, W. (William), 1801-1885
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Asks for a copy of an article on the geology of Palestine. Concerning an archaeological expedition to Palestine.
  - Letter to [George John] Romanes, 7x4-1/2; Foster, Myles Birket, 1825-1899
    Shelford, A.L.S. 1p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Gives opinion of two artists.
  - Letter to ----., 7x4-1/2; Halford, Henry, Sir, bart., 1766-1844
    A.L.S. 1p. Fragment. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Concerning patients. On same sheet as [Sir H.Halford] to ----; n.d.
  - Letter to ----., 7x4-1/2; Halford, Henry, Sir, bart., 1766-1844
    A.L. 1p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Lists his whereabouts for the future months. Will see Sir Robert Peel. On same sheet is fragment of letter from Sir H. Halford to ----; n.d.
  - Letter to Sir James [Paget], 7x4-1/2; Klein, E.
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Asks for has signature on the enclosed and that it be returned to him.
  - Letter to Mr. Paget, 6-3/4x4-1/2; Lankester, E. Ray, Sir, (Edwin Ray), 1847-1929
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Accepts position in the new society.
  - Letter to Sir James Paget, bart., 7x4-1/2; Lewes, George Henry, 1817-1878
    Monday. A.L.S. 2p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Will not be at home but will arrange any date Lady Paget might wish.
  - Letter to [Sir] James Paget, 7x4-1/2; Lewes, George Henry, 1817-1878
    Wednesday. A.L.S. 1p. (see Sir James paget. Collection.) Accepts invitation to dinner to meet Czermak.
  - Letter to [Sir James Paget], 7-1/4x4-1/2; Prestwich, Joseph, 1812-1896
    London, Friday. A.L.S. 1p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Is called away, but hopes to be back when he calls.
  - Shorthand notes [on religion?]., 6x3-1/2; Priestley, Joseph, 1733-1804
    A.D. 2p.,end. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...)
  - Letter to ----, 7x4-1/2; Roupell, M.
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...)
  - Letter to Dr. Dawson Turner, 7x4-1/2; Rutherford, William G. (William Gunion), 1853-1907
    Tuesday. A.L.S. 1p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Will visit Wednesday at 11:40 AM.
  - Letter to [Sir James] Paget., 7-1/4x4-1/2; Simpson, James Young, Sir, 1811-1870
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Introduces a young surgeon.
  - Letter to ----, 10x8; Stephenson, Robert, 1772-1850
    A.L.S. 1p. Incomplete and mutilated. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...)
  - Letter to Frederick Paget, 8x5; Turner, Dawson, 1775-1858
    Monday. A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Invites him to dinner.
  - Calling card addressed to Sir James Paget., 2-1/4x3-1/2; Virchow, Rudolf Ludwig Karl, 1821-1902
    A.D.S. 1p. (see Sir James Paget. Collection...) Introduces Miyake of Tokio university.